Hi,you guys.
我來了
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Well,it's just.. It's one of these situations that I just hate.
又是那種很討厭的狀況
A massage client gave me three tickets...
有一個客人給我三張票
to the Helmut Peltz Exhibit at the Morgan Chase Museum.
去摩根卻斯博物館看展覽
Now you're thinking you gotta sleep with him.
你覺得你得跟他上床
No. No. It's just that he gave me three tickets and there are six of us.
不是，他給我三張票 但是我們有六個人
-I'll give up my ticket. -Me too.
我棄權 我也是
Okay. That's so generous.
你們真大方
And I think Ross is generous too.
羅斯應該也很大方
Great! Then it's just us girls.
太好了，那我們女生自己去
-Great. -Yeah.
太好了
So what is the exhibit?
是什麼展覽？
It's mostly just photographs...
主要是...
of lesbian love scenes interspersed with video games and free sandwiches.
女同志性愛攝影展 還可以打電動，吃免費三明治
Oh,man!
討厭啦
-Hi. -Hi.
Hey,Ross,listen.
羅斯
Chandler got you out of going to the lesbian sandwich museum this weekend.
錢德說你週末 不想去女同志三明治博物館
Thanks,but I have plans. Elizabeth and I are going out of town.
謝謝，我有節目了 伊麗莎白和我要出城去
-That's great! -Yeah.
太好了
Think about all the money that you're gonna make.
你可以大賺一筆
Why? What?
什麼意思？
Well,her father pays you for babysitting,right?
是她爸找你去當保姆對吧？
That's funny. But maybe it's time to move on.
真好笑，但你們也該有所長進
You know,let it go. Stop it!
別再鬧了
Besides,Rachel's going out with Elizabeth's father...
況且瑞秋在和她爸交往
so he's much older than she is.
而他比她大多了
Looks like I'm not the only one interested in fossils.
看來不只是我對化石有興趣
All that does is remind us that you're interested in fossils.
這種話只會提醒我們 你對化石有興趣
Okay,okay.
好吧
Rachel's gonna need to yell sweet nothings in his ear.
瑞秋想和他甜言蜜語 可得用吼的
-Ross? -Come on! That's funny.
羅斯 拜託，這句很好笑啊
Because he's gonna.. He's got,like,a hearing aid.
因為他戴助聽器，因為…
Because he's all old.
因為他很老
One second.
失陪一下
Okay,look,Ross.
聽著，羅斯
Just so you know, since Lizzie likes you so much...
因為麗莎很喜歡你
I've accepted the fact that you're dating her.
我決定接受你們交往的事
Really? That's great.
真的？太好了 是啊
Yeah,but then I changed my mind.
但後來我又反悔了
I'm funny like that.
我就是這麼善變
So I told Lizzie,now I'm telling you.
我已經告訴她，現在我告訴你
I don't want you seeing my daughter anymore.
我不希望你再和我女兒見面
Look,I realize it upsets you.
好，我知道你很不高興
Yes,it does.
沒錯
But Elizabeth and I are both adults...
但伊麗莎白和我都是成年人
so I don't think there's anything you can do about it.
所以你也莫可奈何
I'll tell the university about your relationship and have you fired.
我會告訴學校你們在交往 讓你被開除
Oh,a man with a plan!
有備而來喔
The One Where Paul's The Man
本集播出：「大逆轉」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
This is so exciting. You can get your picture back up on the wall of fame.
好興奮喔 你的照片又要重回名人牆了
He's got all the big actors.
就是啊，這裡什麼大明星都有
It was so cool when I was up there.
之前在牆上時好快樂
Me and Jim Belushi would just be cracking up about something.
我經常和吉姆貝路西說笑
I get fired off Days of Our Lives and he takes me down.
後來我被「我們的歲月」開除 照片被拿下來
Now he's just laughing at me.
現在他都嘲笑我
Look at him. That smug Belushi bastard!
你看那個自鳴得意的混蛋
Okay. Maybe when they put your picture back up...
也許你可以掛在...
they could put you by Matt Lauer.
麥特勞爾旁邊
Look at him just smiling at me.
你看他在對我微笑
Yeah,I know. We'd be great together.
我知道，我們會很速配
-So I'm back. -Who are you?
我回來了 你是誰？
Joey Tribbiani.
喬伊崔比亞尼
From the wall?
我之前上過牆
Okay, maybe this will jog your memory.
也許這樣你會想起來
Okay,anyway.
總之
I'm ready to go back up on the wall. I'm the star of a new TV show.
我可以回牆上了 我主演了一出新戲
-Show me in the TV book. -It's not on TV yet.
哪一出？指給我看  還沒上檔
Well,then it's not on the wall yet.
那你就還不能上牆
Okay,fine. I will bring you a tape.
好吧，我拿錄影帶給你看
So,now,do you have any of Matt Lauer's clothes?
你手邊有麥特勞爾的衣服嗎？
Maybe? Just ones that haven't been cleaned yet?
還沒洗過的？
God.
I love museums.
我好喜歡來博物館
-Soaking up all the culture. -Yeah.
接受文化熏陶
-Where do you want to start? -The gift shop!
要先去哪裡？ 禮品販賣部
-And then lunch. -Yes,but I can't eat too much.
然後去吃飯  好，但我不能吃太多
Paul's taking me out to dinner tonight. He said he has a big surprise planned.
保羅今晚要帶我去吃飯 他說會有個大驚喜
Do you think maybe he's gonna tell you he's gay?
他會不會要說他是同性戀？
What? No,why?
什麼？為什麼？
No reason. That would just be a really big surprise,right?
不為什麼，那樣真的會很驚喜
You could put the aisle over here and have the wedding ceremony over here.
紅毯可以鋪在這邊 然後在這邊證婚
I didn't know you could get married here.
原來這裡可以結婚
This would be a beautiful place to get married.
這裡當禮堂的確很美
But I wouldn't put the aisle there. And I would never have the ceremony there.
但我不會把紅毯鋪在那邊 更不會在那邊證婚
You'd have the ceremony under a beautiful arch.
應該在這個漂亮的拱門下證婚
May I help you?
有什麼事嗎？
Sorry. Didn't mean to interrupt. It's just such a beautiful space.
抱歉打斷你 這裡很美
-Do you do a lot of weddings? -Yes,we're popular.
經常舉辦婚禮嗎？ 是的，這裡很受歡迎
There's a two-year waiting list. Sorry.
預約已經排到2年後，抱歉
Monica,you should put your name down for this place.
摩妮卡，你也應該去預約
What? Are you crazy?
什麼？你瘋了嗎？
I'm not getting married. I'm not even engaged.
我又不結婚，我甚至還沒訂婚
But there's a two-year wait. What if you get engaged in two years?
但反正要等2年 要是你2年後訂了婚
Then you've got to wait another two years?
還得再等2年
That's four years. Chandler's not gonna wait that long.
那就4年了 錢德才不會等那麼久
He's gonna find somebody else.
他會去找別人
Someone who did put their name on the list.
某個有預約的人
It can't hurt to put your name down.
先預約又不會怎樣
If,in two years, you're not engaged, you just don't use it.
要是2年後沒訂婚就放棄不用
I guess there is no harm in putting my name down.
先預約的確不會怎樣
I'm gonna do it too.
我也要預約
Me too!
我也要
-Really? Who would you marry? -I don't have anyone right now.
真的？你要嫁給誰？ 我不知道， 我現在還沒有對象
Oh,Phoebe.
菲比
Don't feel too sorry for me. At least my boyfriend isn't gay.
別為我難過 至少我的男朋友不是同性戀
Phoebe,that's not..
菲比，你根本…
Don't even get me started on yours.
別逼我批評你家那個
-Did you watch the tape of my show? -I did.
你看過錄影帶了嗎？ 看過了
-Let's get me back up there. -You don't go up on the wall.
好，讓我回牆上吧  不行，你不能上牆
-What? But you saw the show. -lt was very offensive to my people.
什麼？ 但你看過我的戲了  對，它冒犯了我的同胞
Dry cleaners?
乾洗店老闆嗎？
Russians. It showed them as terrorists and villains.
俄國人 它把他們演成恐怖分子和壞蛋
Okay,okay. Look,you got Harrison Ford up there!
好，你看，你有哈里遜福特
That's right. Mr. Ford is a very good customer.
沒錯，福特先生是個好顧客
He brings us a lot of clothes. You bring nothing!
他帶很多衣服來，你兩手空空
Okay,that may be true.
或許吧
But in Air Force One,okay, the Russians were terrorists and evil!
但在「空軍一號」裡 俄國人是恐怖分子，很邪惡
And plus,he kills a bunch of them. That's offensive to Russians.
他還殺了一堆俄國人 那樣很冒犯你們
-I've never seen it. -You should. It's great!
我沒看過 你應該要看，很贊
This place is really beautiful.
這裡真的好漂亮
I've been coming here since I was a kid. This used to be my grandma's.
對啊，我從小就常來 這裡以前是我奶奶家
The only thing I got from my grandmother was her eyes.
我只遺傳了我奶奶的眼睛
I mean,not her actual eyeballs.
我不是說她的眼珠子
But people say that my eyes look...
大家都說我的眼睛…
Do you wanna make out?
要不要親熱？
Sure.
好啊
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Yeah. I was just thinking about your father.
我只是想到你爸爸
Well,whatever works for you.
只要你能興奮就好
No.
不是
He just really freaked me out before.
他有點把我嚇到了
So we have to hide our relationship from one more person.
我們得再多瞞著一個人
Big deal.
那又怎樣
Besides,we've had fun hiding it.
況且我們一直很樂在其中
Yeah.
也對
-Yeah? -You brought protection,right?
你有準備防護措施嗎？
Why,are there,like,bears or something?
怎麼了？這裡有熊嗎？
Protection. Yeah. No,yeah. That.. That I forgot.
你是說那個，沒有，我忘了
I can't believe I brought two cans of bug spray and forgot that.
我居然帶了兩瓶防蚊液 卻忘了帶套子
-I'll run to the store and get some. -I'm the guy. I'll get it.
那我去買 不，我是男人，我去買
-Do you know where the store is? -No.
你知道商店在哪裡嗎？ 不知道
Do you wanna ride around town on my little pink bicycle?
你想騎粉紅腳踏車逛大街嗎？
A little bit.
有點想
I'll be back in 10 minutes. Get in the hot tub and I'll meet you there.
我10分鐘後回來 你先進浴缸裡等我
Okay.
好
Oh,my God! What a great surprise! This is such a beautiful house!
天哪，好棒的驚喜 這棟房子好漂亮
Thank you. It used to be my mother's. This is the kitchen.
謝謝，這是我媽的房子 這裡是廚房
-Hey,Chandler. -Hey,Joe.
錢德 喬伊
Everybody's gotta be doing something.
人總得找事情做
You've reached Monica and Chandler's.
這裡是摩妮卡和錢德的家
If you're listening to this message, we're probably screening.
如果你聽到這則留言 我們可能在篩選電話
Yeah,we are.
就是
Hi,this is Hildy from the Morgan Chase Museum.
我是摩根卻斯博物館的海蒂
I'm calling for Monica Geller. I wanted to let her know that there was a cancellation.
我要找摩妮卡蓋勒 有人取消預約
If she's still interested in having the Bing-Geller wedding in our facility...
如果她還想在我們這裡辦婚禮
...it is available..
現在有空了
This is Chandler Bing! This is Chandler Bing!
我是錢德賓，我是錢德賓
Yes,the groom.
是的，我是新郎
No,not the groom!
不，我不是
It's so secluded up here.
這裡好幽靜
I know. That's why I like it here.
我知道，所以我喜歡這裡
I feel like we're the only two people in the world.
全世界好像只剩我們兩個人
Sorry.
抱歉
What's the matter,honey?
怎麼了？
-Did you see a little mouse? -No! Big bear! Big bear outside!
你看到老鼠了嗎？ 不是，大熊，外面有大熊
I think I..
-Actually,would you go check on that? -We don't have any bears here.
你要不要…要不要去看一下？ 親愛的，這裡沒有熊
Well,okay.
好吧
Would you get me a Diet Coke?
幫我倒杯健怡可樂好嗎
-Okay. Be right back. -Okay.
好，我馬上回來 好
-What are you doing here? -What are you doing here?
你在這裡幹嘛？ 你又在這裡幹嘛？
-I came with Paul! -Yeah. I recognized the ankles.
我是跟保羅來的 我認出他的腳踝了
-Where is Elizabeth? -She's at the store.
伊麗莎白呢？ 她去買東西
-You make the girl go to the store? -Do I know where the store is?
你讓女生去買東西？ 我知道商店在哪裡嗎？
Hurry up. Get out.
快出來
Here you go,honey.
拿去吧
-Thank you! -Diet Coke.
謝謝你 健怡可樂
Ice.
冰塊
I need ice.
我要冰塊
Okay.
好
-Thank you. -Be right back.
謝謝你 我馬上回來
Okay.
You and your ice.
又是冰塊這一招
Get out! Get out! Go! Come on!
出來，快點
No,not in there! Not in there! He's in there!
不行，他在那裡面
-Did you really hear a bear? -Go!
你真的聽到熊叫了嗎？ 進去啦
Here you go,honey.
來了
One Diet Coke with ice.
一杯加冰的健怡可樂
Thank you.
謝謝
I am so happy that you're here.
真高興有你在
-Here I am! -Elizabeth!
我回來了 伊麗莎白
Look! Elizabeth's here!
看，伊麗莎白來了
Who were you talking to?
你在跟誰說話？
You guys?
你們啊
How did you know we were here?
你怎麼知道我們在這裡？
She obviously saw the tire tracks leading up to the closed garage.
她一定是看到往車庫的方向 有輪胎痕
Obviously.
是啊
What are you doing here?
你來這裡幹什麼？
Did you come up here to work on that term paper or something?
你是來這裡趕報告的嗎？
Yeah.
沒錯
Well,why don't you go in that room and do your homework?
那你去那個房間寫吧
I wouldn't do it in there. That's my dad's bedroom.
我不會去那個房間寫 那是我爸的臥房
That's your dad's bedroom.
那是你爸的臥房
That's your dad's bedroom!
Why are you yelling?
你幹嘛這麼大聲？
That Diet Coke,I think, just straight to my head!
這杯健怡可樂讓我好high
Hi,honey.
親愛的
See you later.
待會兒見
Wait. I bought groceries. I was gonna make you dinner.
我買了東西要幫你煮晚餐
Well,next time,ask!
下次先問我
Or at least wait for me to ask!
或等我先開口
Hi,this is Hildy from the Morgan Chase Museum.
我是摩根卻斯博物館的海蒂
-I'm calling for Monica Geller. -Oh,no.
我要找摩妮卡蓋勒 完了
I wanted to let her know that there was a cancellation.
有人取消預約
If she's still interested in having the Bing-Geller wedding in our facility...
如果她還想在我們這裡辦婚禮
it is available....
現在有空了
Please. He didn't hear it!
拜託，他沒聽到，他沒聽到
This is Chandler Bing! This is Chandler Bing!
我是錢德賓，我是錢德賓
No!
不！
Can I help you?
有什麼事嗎？
Yeah,where's the guy who decides whose pictures go up on the wall?
決定誰能上牆的那個人呢？
-He's not here right now. -You're kidding me!
他現在不在 不會吧
Make sure you tell him that Joey Tribbiani stopped by to drop off all these clothes.
記得告訴他 喬伊崔比亞尼帶了一堆衣服來
I'm an actor. I'm trying to get my picture on the wall.
我是個演員 我想讓我的照片上牆
You know,there are two people who could get your picture up there.
其實有兩個人能決定這件事
Oh,really?
是嗎？
Well,maybe you and I go out for drinks.
也許我們應該去喝一杯
You're the other one,right?
你是另外一個人吧？
So,Lizzie, are you planning on staying the night?
麗莎，你今晚要留下來嗎？
No,no. Believe me, I'm leaving as soon as possible.
不，我要盡快離開
Good. Not that we don't want you to stay. Obviously,you're welcome.
那好…不是我們不要你留下來
How much more homework do you have?
你還有多少功課？
I just have one problem left that I do not know how to solve.
只剩一個問題不知道怎麼解決
Rachel, maybe you wanna come upstairs and help me figure it out?
瑞秋，也許你可以上樓來幫我
Really?
是嗎？
Okay.
Okay,I'll go upstairs...
好，我上樓
if you get me something from the car.
你去車上幫我拿東西
What do you need from the car?
你要拿什麼東西？
Surprise me.
給我驚喜啊
Okay.
好
So you're gonna be in the car! I will be upstairs!
你要去車上，我要去樓上
That's where everybody's gonna be!
這就是目前的狀況
Just relax. Relax,Paul. You're doing great.
放輕鬆，放輕鬆 你表現得很好
She likes you.
她喜歡你
I think she likes you. She likes you.
她…她喜歡你
You know why? Because you're a neat guy.
為什麼？因為你粉贊
You are the man.
你是男子漢
You are the man!
Still got it.
還是很有料
Still sexy.
很性感
You're just a love machine.
你是個愛情機器
我是個愛情機器 我只為你服務，寶貝
Showtime.
上場了
我是個愛情機器，寶貝
-Phoebe? -Yeah?
菲比
-Have you seen Chandler? -No,why?
你有見到錢德嗎？ 沒有，怎麼了？
The museum called and said that there was a cancellation...
博物館那個女人打來說 有人取消預約
and that we could move up our wedding. And Chandler heard.
我們可以提前舉行婚禮 結果錢德聽見了
I know. How bad is this?
就是啊，你覺得有多嚴重？
Well,with a regular guy, it's bad. With Chandler, oh, dear God!
對一般男人來說很嚴重 但是對錢德…我的天哪
I know! And he totally freaked out. I can't find him anywhere!
我知道，他被嚇到了 我到處都找不到他
-What are you gonna do? -I'm never going to listen to you again.
你要怎麼辦？ 反正我再也不聽你的話了
"What harm can it do if you put your name down?"
「先預約又不會怎樣」
-Rachel said that. -Well,Rachel's not here!
那是瑞秋說的 瑞秋不在這裡
You really think she put your picture up already?
她真的已經把你掛上去了？
Did she put my picture up?
這是什麼話？
You kidding, after the date we had?
那次約會之後
I wouldn't be surprised if she put 10 of my pictures up there.
她就算掛十張我都不會驚訝
Except for the fact that I only gave her one. I don't know where she'd get the other nine.
只不過我只給了她一張 不知道她要去哪裡再弄九張
Here it is!
在這裡
Joey,why did you sign it "son of a bitch"?
喬伊，你為什麼要簽「混蛋」
-I didn't do that. Who would do that? -Son of a bitch!
我沒有啊，這是誰幹的？
Okay. Maybe ask this guy.
混蛋 問他好了
-You! Get out of my shop! -What did he do?
你，滾出我的店 他做了什麼？
-He went out with my wife! -Joey!
他跟我老婆約會  喬伊
I did not go out with your wife! Okay?
我沒有跟你老婆約會，好嗎？
I went out with her.
我是跟她約會
That's my wife!
她就是我老婆
I'm not pointing at her,no. I'm pointing at her.
我指的不是她，我指的是她
"Zelda McMurray."
賽妲麥默瑞
Who the hell..? How did she get up there?!
誰啊？她憑什麼上牆？
Get out!
-Well,we should go. -Yeah.
我們還是走好了
Ross?
羅斯？羅斯？
Elizabeth!
伊麗莎白
Okay. I'm gonna go out this window.
好，我從窗戶爬出去
I'll meet you at the front door. Tell them you're going home.
我們前門見，你就說你要回家
-Okay. -Wait! No,don't go in there!
好  等等，別進去
Don't go in there! I need another soda!
別進去！ 我還要喝汽水
Ross!
羅斯
Oh,my God,Ross! What in heaven's name are you doing here?
天哪，羅斯，你在這裡幹什麼
And that is why we cannot see each other anymore.
所以我們不能再見面了
Ross, you and I are gonna have to have a little talk.
羅斯，我們得好好談一談
-Daddy, I..  -You're next!
爸 接著就是你
Okay. I didn't know he was here.
好，我不知道他有來
Let me just see if I got this straight.
讓我把話問清楚
I tell you to stay away from my daughter or I'll have you fired.
我叫你離我女兒遠一點 否則就讓你被開除
What you heard was: "Take my daughter...
結果你聽到的是
come up to my country house and ruin my weekend with Rachel."
「帶我女兒到我鄉下的別墅」 「破壞我和瑞秋的週末」
-Please,Paul. Just let me explain. -No! Let me explain! Fired!
-拜託，你聽我說  -不，你聽我說：開除
Okay,fine. Fine. Have me fired.
好，開除就開除
But I want you to know...
我只想你知道
that you and I are not all that different. I mean...
我們也沒那麼不同
I,too,am a "neat guy."
我也粉贊
What?
什麼？
And I,too...
我也是...
am "just a love machine."
愛情機器
-Let me show you the guest room. -Okay.
我帶你去客房
I'm so sorry. Please stop freaking out.
對不起，你別再害怕了
I'm not freaking out.
我沒有害怕啊
Why would I? A woman named Hildy called and said we were getting married.
我幹嘛害怕？ 有個叫海蒂的說我們要結婚了
But that happens every day.
但這是常有的事
Honey,we were at this beautiful place...
親愛的，那個地方很漂亮
and I just put our names down for fun.
我只是預約好玩的
-I mean,what's the harm in that? -Right here.
-會怎樣嗎  -會這樣
Please don't think I was trying to pressure you.
錢德，你千萬別以為我想逼婚
-Phoebe and Rachel thought.. -Phoebe and Rachel?
菲比和瑞秋覺得… 菲比和瑞秋
So the people that knew about our wedding before me were you...
所以比我早知道我們要結婚的 有你...
Phoebe and Rachel, Hildy, and some band called the Starlight Magic Seven...
菲比和瑞秋 海蒂 和一個叫星光魔力的樂團
who are available, by the way.
對了，他們也有空
It was a mistake.
我錯了
Please don't take this to mean anything, because it doesn't.
我完全沒有那個意思
Okay.
好吧
Really?
真的？
Yes. If it really doesn't mean anything, because you know I'm not ready.
如果你真的沒有那個意思 你知道我還沒準備好
I know.
我知道
Okay.
好
All right.
I'm gonna go tell Joey that you're back.
我去告訴喬伊你回來了
We were really worried about you.
我們剛才好擔心
And that guy that never delivered his burrito?
不是有個人叫了卷餅沒送來？
He thought there was some sort of connection.
他以為跟那件事有關
Did she buy it?
她相信了嗎？
Totally.
相信了
-So did Hildy show you the place? -Yeah. It's beautiful.
海蒂有帶你參觀嗎？ 有，那裡好漂亮
I can't believe you're gonna ask Monica to marry you.
你居然要跟摩妮卡求婚了
I know.
就是啊
-Hey,Gunther. -Take these cappuccinos to table 11.
阿甘 把這些卡布奇諾端到11桌
And that guy wants some biscotti.
那個男的要意大利脆棒
I just actually came in for a cup of coffee.
我只是要外帶一杯咖啡
Do you still work here?
你還在這裡打工嗎？
No. I quit a long time ago.
沒有，我早就不做了
Did I forget to tell you that? I'm sorry.
我沒有告訴你嗎？抱歉
-Cool. I was gonna fire you anyway. -Great!
反正我也打算開除你 太好了